Guide to the Edgar Eugene Robinson Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Professional Correspondence Files, 1910-1952
  - ( This is War - The Roots of the Conflict, etc.), 1950-51 (Box 27, Folder 477)
    Publication in Vital Speeches
  - (W - Z), 1950-51 (Box 27, Folder 478)
    J. B. Wolf, J. P. Weter, Letter re Qualifications of Men in Dept. (To E. Faye Wilson), Gerald T. White ( The Historian), World Affairs Council of Northern California, O. O. Winther.
  - (A), 1951-52 (Box 28, Folder 479)
    American Historical Association (National registration - The Humanities and Social Sciences).
  - (B), 1951-52 (Box 28, Folder 480)
    Bancroft Library, A. C. Krey (re Vaughn Bornet), R. Butow, Vaughn Bornet.
  - (C), 1951-52 (Box 28, Folder 481)
    W. J. Campbell (Support of Eisenhower, American History requirements), J. E. Caswell, College of Physicians and Surgeons, Census Bureau, A. H. Clodius, William H. Hobbs, Letter to Meredith Crawford (re Psychological Warfare).
  - (D), 1951-52 (Box 28, Folder 482)
    Charles O. Donahue (re Materials Deposited in Hoover Library), Letter to Maurice T. Dooling, Jr., (re Commonwealth Club Gold Medal Literature Award).
  - (E), 1951-52 (Box 28, Folder 483)
    Edward M. Earle, Educational Testing Service.
  - (F), 1951-52 (Box 28, Folder 484)
    G. A. Frykman
  - (G), 1951-52 (Box 28, Folder 485)
    John Gange, F. H. Garver.
  - (H), 1951-52 (Box 28, Folder 486)
    W. T. Hutchinson, Betty Hassell
  - (I - J), 1951-52 (Box 28, Folder 487)
    Stanford Fund, W. R. Jacobs, C. Irvine.
  - (K), 1951-52 (Box 28, Folder 488)
    F. V. Keesling, A. C. Krey, L. K. Koontz Memorial Award.
  - (L), 1951-52 (Box 28, Folder 489)
    R. E. Langer (American History requirements on Wisconsin), E. W. Lyon, R. Littler.
  - (M), 1951-52 (Box 28, Folder 490)
    Milestones Magazine, Beverly McAnear
  - (N - O), 1951-52 (Box 28, Folder 491)
    Society of American Historians
  - (P), 1951-52 (Box 28, Folder 492)
    recommendation of Rullie E. Popping, Earl S. Pomeroy.
  - (R), 1951-52 (Box 28, Folder 493)
    Nicholas Roosevelt, retirement of Prof. Robinson, A. H. Clodius, E. Rothwell.
  - (E. E. R. Publications), 1951-52 (Box 28, Folder 494)
    Book reviews
  - (S), 1951-52 (Box 28, Folder 495)
    report of Committee on Lower Division, Charles C. Scott, James W. Shannon, J. E. W. Sterling, L. J. Stellman (re Frank Pixley).
  - (T - Z), 1951-52 (Box 28, Folder 496)
    Dorothy L. Thompson, O. O. Winther, James P. Weter.
  - (Institute of American History Plans) The Foundation for American Studies, Stanford Social Education Investigation Workshop, 1941 (Box 28, Folder 497)
  - 1928 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    Correspondence, including John S. P. Tatlock, Harvard, Department of English.
  - 1929 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    Correspondence, including Ralph Hawkins, Hopkins Marine Station.
  - 1950 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    Correspondence, including Naval research Laboratory concerning technical report to be written by Robinson, Budget statements for Navy contract, benefits and social security.
  - 1951 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    Correspondence, including President J.E.W. Sterling, Edward Hohfeld, Controller concerning retirement.
  - A-L, 1962 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    Correspondence, including Professor Thomas Bailey, Luther Evens, Librarian of congress, John Gange, Controller's office.
  - M-Z, 1952 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    Correspondence, including Professor Allan Nevins, Jerry O'Callaghen, Nicholas Roosevelt, President Sterling, Professor Nathan Van Patten.
  - A-K, 1953 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    Correspondence, including Merle Alderman, Vaughn Bornet, John E. Baker, Herman Blum, Thomas Bailey, W. J. Campbell, Professor Harold Bacon, Edith Dobie, Maurice Dooling, Jr., Alex De Conde, Joseph Dixon, Luther Evans, John Gange, Herbert Hoover, Francis V. Keeling, Robert Kelley.
  - L-Z, 1953 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    Correspondence, including J. A. Larson, J. Paul Leonard, Marvin McHee, John Francis Neylan, O. C. Oberst, Jerry O'Callaghan, Roy Peel, Elmer E. Robinson. President Sterling, Gordan Watkins, Walter Yust.
  - A-L, 1954 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    Correspondence, including Robert Butow, Professor Harold Bacon, Professor Thomas Bailey, Alex De Conde, Luther Evans, Herbert Hoover, letter concerning Lincoln Club Speech.
  - M-Z, 1954 (Box 52, Folder 10)
    Correspondence, including Michael Polito, President Sterling, James Weter, Stewart Ward, Walter Yust.
  - A-K, 1955 (Box 52, Folder 11)
    Correspondence, including Professor Harold Bacon, Donald Bean, Professor Thomas Bailey, John J. Caldwell, Joe Dixon, Goodwin J. Knight.
  - L-Z, 1955 (Box 52, Folder 12)
    Correspondence, including Osgood Murdock, A. Hubbard Moffitt, Nicholas Roosevelt, President Sterling, Walter Lippmann, Henry R. Luce, John Neylan, Jerry O'Callaghan, Michael Polito, I. James Quillen, Max Thelen, Harry S. Truman, Stewart Ward, James Weter.
  - A-L, 1956 (Box 52, Folder 13)
    Correspondence, including Merle Aldermann, William F. Buckley Jr., Leland Cutler, Edwin Coman, Joe Dixon, Harlund Fuller, Edward Hohfeld, Herbert Hoover, Louis P. Lochner.
  - M-Z, 1956 (Box 52, Folder 14)
    Correspondence, including David Mearns, Michael Polito, Nicholas Roosevelt, President Sterling, Professor Theodore E. Treutlem, Stuart Ward.
  - A-J, 1957 (Box 52, Folder 15)
    Correspondence, including Clinton P. Anderson, Professor Thomas Bailey, Edwin Coman, Leland Cutler, Kenneth Culbertson.
  - K-Z, 1957 (Box 52, Folder 16)
    Correspondence, including Edward Hohfeld, George Hammond, W. J. Hutchinson, John F. Kennedy, Louis P. Lochner, David C. Mearns, Rixford Snyder, R. C. Swank, President Sterling, H. Donald Winbigler, James P. Weter.
  - A-B, 1958 (Box 52, Folder 17)
    Correspondence, including Merle Alderman and Vaughn Bornet.
  - C-Z, 1958 (Box 52, Folder 18)
    Correspondence, including John Young, John E. Caswell, Frank Dickinson, John Dodge, Herbert Hoover, Thomas Hart, President Sterling.
  - 1959 (Box 52, Folder 19)
    Correspondence, including Vaughn Bornet, William Johnson, Thomas Martin, President Sterling.
  - 1960 (Box 52, Folder 20)
    Correspondence, including Vaughn Bornet, Paul Edwards, Herbert Hoover.
  - 1961 (Box 52, Folder 21)
    Correspondence, including Vaughn Bornet, Edward Hohfeld, Edward J. Day, Leslie H. Fishel, Jerry O'Callaghan.
  - A-F, 1962 (Box 52, Folder 22)
    Correspondence, including Howard Brooke, Vaughn Bornet, Joseph Dixon, Alex De Conde, Glenn S. Dumke, Harlin Fuller.
  - G-Z, 1962 (Box 52, Folder 23)
    Correspondence, including Edward Hohfeld.
  - A-E, 1963 (Box 52, Folder 24)
    Correspondence, including Vaughn Bornet, Alex DeConde, John V. Dodge, John P. Everett.
  - F-Z, 1963 (Box 52, Folder 25)
    Correspondence, including John Gange, Thomas Kuchel, Martin B. Travis, Stuart Ward, Harry Winton.
  - A-L, 1964 (Box 52, Folder 26)
    Correspondence, including Vaughn Bornet, J. Hart Clinton, Alexander DeConde.
  - M-Z, 1964 (Box 52, Folder 27)
    Correspondence, including Martin Travis, Raymond O'Connor, Edward Hofeld, Nicholas Roosevelt.
  - A-H, 1965 (Box 52, Folder 28)
    Correspondence, including Hilary Crawford, J. Hart Clinton, Alex DeConde, Arnold Dolin, J.G.E. Hopkins, Colonel James Hughes.
  - I-Z, 1965 (Box 52, Folder 29)
    Correspondence, including Raymond O'Connor, Charles N. Stabler, Homer Spence, Leon Seltzer, Martin B. Travis.
  - 1966 (Box 52, Folder 30)
    Correspondence, including Vaughn Bornet, John Caswell, Alex Deconde, Raymond O'Connor, Albert Nodda, Paul Kegley, President Sterling, Martin Travis, Max Thelen, William Wood.
  - 1967 (Box 52, Folder 31)
    Correspondence, including Thomas Bailey, Alex DeConde, Thomas Hart, Robert L. Levin, Raymond O'Connor, Professor David Potter, Nicholas Roosevelt, Homer Spence, Martin B. Travis, Max Thelen.
  - 1968-71 (Box 52, Folder 31a)
    Correspondence, including David Harris and George Knoles
  - Robinson--Encyclopedia Britiannica, Correspondence (Box 52, Folder 32)
  - Robinson--J. Brooks, B. Parker Estate (Box 52, Folder 33)
  - Commonwealth Club (Box 52, Folder 34)
  - English Speaking Union (Box 52, Folder 35)
  - Robinson--Henry Luce, Correspondence (Box 52, Folder 36)
  - Robinson--Harley Notter, Correspondence (Box 52, Folder 37)
  - Robinson--Harley Notter, Correspondence (Box 52, Folder 38)
  - Robinson--O'Callaghan, Correspondence (Box 52, Folder 39)
  - Robinson--Mark requa, Correspondence (Box 52, Folder 40)
  - Letters re: Roosevelt Leadership (Box 52, Folder 41)
  - Roosevelt Leadership, correspondence with publisher (Box 52, Folder 41a)
  - Robinson--Nicholas Roosevelt, Correspondence (Box 52, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence: Callaghan, Jerry A. to Mrs. Edgar E. Robinson, 3 March 1979 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence from Frederick Jackson Turner to Edgar E. Robinson
    - 3 April 1909 - 26 December 1911 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - 30 July 1912 - 26 December 1912 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - 4 September 1913 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - 27 April 1914 - 28 October 1914 (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - 17 March 1915 - 24 March 1915 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - 13 January 1916 - 25 June 1916 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - 14 May 1917 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - 19 January 1918 - 12 December 1918 (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - 11 May 1920 - 4 December 1920 (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - 22 November 1923 (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - 3 March 1924 - 12 December 1924 (Box 78, Folder 12)
    - 31 March 1925 - 22 April 1925 (Box 78, Folder 13)
    - 14 January 1929 - 4 February 1929 (Box 78, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 78, Folder 15)
  - Articles on Turner (Box 78, Folder 16)
    - Beard, Charles, The Frontier in American History, 1939
    - Jacob, Wilbur R., Colonial Origins of the United States: The Turnerean View, 1971
    - Jacobs, W. R. Turner's Methodolgy: Multiple Working Hypothesis or Ruling Theory?, 1968
    - Kellog, Louise Phelps, The Passing of a Great Teacher, Frederick J. Turner, 1932
    - Sellery, G. C., The Spirit of Wisconsin, 1937
    - Weaver, John D. A Portrait of the Unconventional Scholar, (N.D.)
  - Notes on Turner's Class (Box 78, Folder 17)
  - Newsclippings on Turner (Box 78, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence and memoirs re Herbert Hoover (Box 78, Folder 19)
  - Herbert Hoover Memorabilia (Box 78, Folder 20)
- Manuscripts and Subject Files
  - Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies (Box 29, Folder [1])
  - National Committee on Food for the Small Democracies (Box 29, Folder [2])
  - Social Science research Conference (Box 29, Folder [3])
  - Social Science research Correspondence (Box 29, Folder [4])
  - Stanford College Plan (Box 29, Folder [5])
  - COMMUNISM: clippings, articles, pamphlets, etc. (Box 30)
  - THE PreSIDENTIAL VOTE (three drafts), 1896-1932 (Box 30)
  - Clippings, articles, pamphlets, etc. on political issues and happenings (Box 30)
  - Papers of several students: (Box 30)
    - J. M. Espinosa, THE PERSONNEL OF THE LA FOLLETTE CANDIDACY OF 1912
      (contains a letter from Oswald Garrison Villard)
    - E. A. White, SOME LITERARY reFLECTIONS ON THE RISE OF THE NEW DEMOCRACY
    - G. H. Knoles, GROVER CLEVELAND AND THE PANIC OF 1893
  - Stowell Diary (Box 30, Folder [1])
  - Hager (Box 30, Folder [2])
  - Allen Johnson (Box 30, Folder [3])
  - H. H. Haight (Box 30, Folder [4])
  - James Lick (Box 30, Folder [5])
  - Manuscripts of earlier writings (about 1915-20) and clippings related to their subject matter. (Box 30)
  - Materials on the works of the committee of tthe Academic Council to aid the Board of Trustees in selection of a president of Stanford University. (Sealed until after death of President Sterling.) (Box 30)
  - Preliminary work (rough drafts, scratch work) for Robinson's writings. (Box 31)
  - Election data and newspaper clippings, along with a few articles and some (partial) rough drafts. (Box 32)
  - Drummond, Helen N. (Box 32, Folder [1])
  - Election, 1936 - (Box 32, Folder [2])
  - Tables (Box 32, Folder [3-4])
  - Presidential government (Box 32, Folder [5])
  - Preface (Box 32, Folder [6])
  - Introduction (Box 32, Folder [7])
  - Summary tables (Box 32, Folder [8-9])
  - General Douglas MacArthur (Box 32, Folder [10-11])
  - Rough notes and drafts for writings and lectures. (Box 33)
  - Robinson's Master's thesis (Box 33)
  - George Hearst (Box 33, Folder [1])
  - Phoebe A. Hearst (Box 33, Folder [2])
  - Isaac Lankershim (Box 33, Folder [3])
  - Pamphlets (Box 33, Folder [4])
  - Brief biographies (Box 33, Folder [5])
  - Lectures - Robinson (Box 33, Folder [6])
  - Value of Opinion in Public Affairs; Citizenship (Box 33, Folder [7])
  - Manuscripts and rough drafts, by chapter (Box 41- 46)
  - Business correspondence resulting from Robinson's work for Encyclopedia Britannica. (Box 47 - 49)
  - Manuscript sources and Notes for Presidential Vote Studies by Professor Edgar E. Robinson. (Box 50)
    Included: They Voted For Roosevelt
    The Presidential Vote
    The Presidential Vote 1936
  - Manuscript sources and Notes for Presidential Vote studies by Professor Edgar E. Robinson. (Box 51)
  - Manuscripts and notes for Hoover Leadership by Professor Edgar E. Robinson. (Box 53-54)
  - Manuscripts and notes for Powers of President in International relations by Professor Edgar E. Robinson. (Box 55)
  - Manuscripts and notes for biography of Ray Lyman Wilbur by Professor Edgar E. Robinson. (Box 56, Folder 1-6)
  - Manuscript and notes for biography of Woodrow Wilson by Professor Edgar E. Robinson. (Box 56, Folder 7-8)
  - The Individual and His Education at Stanford (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - The Economics of Politics (or) This Schizophrenic American (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - A Future for Stanford in Liberal Education (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - Great President of Our Time (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - Andrew Jackson--Historical Drama in Four Acts (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - Institute of World Affairs--The New U.S. in a New World, December 11, 1950 (Box 56, Folder 14)
  - Lincoln Club, Los Angeles, Lincoln 100 Years After, February 12, 1954 (Box 56, Folder 15)
  - Chit Chat Club, On Politics and History, April 14, 1952 (Box 56, Folder 16)
  - Chit Chat Club, Woodrow Wilson, February 11, 1957 (Box 56, Folder 17)
  - Stanford Business Conference, Leadership in America, 1952 (Box 56, Folder 18)
  - Stanford's Role in American History (Box 56, Folder 19)
  - Commonwealth Club, Speech, Democracy and Leadership in the American Foundation, 1956 (Box 56, Folder 20)
  - Lincoln--100 Years After, Addresses, 1954 (Box 56, Folder 21)
  - Stanford's Role in American History (Box 56, Folder 22)
  - What Price History, February 4, 1956 (Box 56, Folder 23)
  - Friends of the Bancroft Library, May, 1956 (Box 56, Folder 24)
  - Tuesday Evening Series, Franklin Delano Roosevelt, October 4, 1955 (Box 56, Folder 25)
  - Foundations of American Nationality, Citizenship Lecture, 1925 (Box 56, Folder 26)
  - The Individual and His Education in the University (Box 56, Folder 27)
  - Robinson--History Department (Box 56, Folder 28)
  - History department, re EER's efforts to have if made a school, 1942-43 (Box 56, Folder 29)
  - report to Commonwealth Club on The Powers of the President in International relations, Parts 1-3 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - report to Commonwealth Club on The Powers of the President in International relations, Part 4 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - report to Commonwealth Club on The Powers of the President in International relations, Part 5 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - report to Commonwealth Club on The Powers of the President in International relations, Parts 6-7 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Commonwealth Club, Literature Award, October 21, 1955 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Commonwealth Club Addresses (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Commonwealth Club, 1963 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Commonwealth Club, 1964 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Commonwealth Club, report to research Committee, 1964 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Commonwealth Club, 1965 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Commonwealth Club, 1966 (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Clippings (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - Clippings (Box 57, Folder 13)
  - Clippings (Box 57, Folder 14)
  - Clippings (Box 57, Folder 15)
  - 1967 Encyclopedia Britannica Material written by Professor Edgar E. Robinson (Box 57, Folder 16)
  - Ideas (Box 57, Folder 17)
  - Ideas (Box 57, Folder 18)
  - Is the American Presidency Obsolete?, 1965 (Box 57, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscript Notes (Box 57, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, [1935?] (Box 57, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Kennedy at Stanford) (Box 57, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 57, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 57, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 57, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1961-63 (Box 57, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1965 (Box 57, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material (Box 57, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material (Box 57, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material (Box 57, Folder 30)
  - Note Cards on Books (Box 57, Folder 31)
  - Organizing for the National Security, 1961 (Box 57, Folder 32)
  - Personal File, Edgar E. Robinson (Box 57, Folder 33)
  - Phi Alpha Theta--Honorary Membership, 1948 (Box 57, Folder 34)
  - President Wilson's Election, 1916 (Box 57, Folder 35)
  - receipts (Box 57, Folder 36)
  - reviews (Box 57, Folder 37)
  - Saturday review, December 18, 1959 (Box 57, Folder 38)
  - Stanford's Role in American History, Speech, November 30, 1961 (Box 57, Folder 39)
  - The Trend of the Patroleum Industry from Armistice to 1934 (Box 57, Folder 40)
  - Robinson Comments on Vietnam, 1965 (Box 57, Folder 41)
  - Why Vietnam by President Lyndon B. Johnson, 1965 (Box 57, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous Articles about Edgar E. Robinson. (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Articles mentioning Edgar E. Robinson. (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Clippings (of Articles by Schlesinger, Brier, reston, and Lippman) (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Clippings (Miscellaneous re. Politics) (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Clippings (Miscellaneous re. Politics) (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Clippings (The Woodrow Wilson I Knew by Mary Allen Hulbert) (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Johnson, Hiram, correspondence re., 1956-57 (Box 58, Folder 6a)
  - Commonwealth Club (Correspondence and Printed Materials) (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Commonwealth Club-International relations (Correspondence and Clippings) (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Description of Courses given by Edgar E. Robinson. (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Memorial Church-Chaplains Advisory Committee (Correspondence and Articles) (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Materials Collected by Edgar E. Robinson. (with some annotations) (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence re. Powers of the President in Foreign Affairs. (Article in Stanford Today) (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence re. Powers of the President in Foreign Affairs. (Book) (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Clippings re. Powers of the President in Foreign Affairs. (reviews) (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Speeches by Edgar E. Robinson. (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - University Affairs (Publications and Correspondence) (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Independent study plan at Stanford, publicity re, 1931 (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Turner, F.J.--New England, 1830-1850 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Turner, F.J.--reprints of Articles about or by Turner. (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Turner, F.J.--reprints of Articles about Turner. (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Turner, F.J.--reprints and Articles re. the Turner Thesis. (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Turner, F.J.--Student Papers on the Turner Thesis. (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Turner, F.J.--reprints and Articles by Turner. (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Turner, F.J.--Student Papers on the Turner Thesis, 1945 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Turner, F.J.--Newspaper Clippings re. Turner. (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Turner, F.J.--Bibliographies of his Works. (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Manuscript of Herbert Hoover President of the United States (working copy) (Box 79, Folder 1-6)
  - Bailey's comment (Box 79, Folder 7)
- Class Materials and Lectures
  - Lecture notes, reading lists, seating charts, examinations, syllabuses, relevant clippings and articles, etc., for: Civilization in the United States in the Twentieth Century; History 31; History 116; History 168, 169, 170; and History 161 (Box 34)
  - Lecture notes, reading lists, seating charts, examinations, syllabuses, relevant clippings and articles, etc., for History 132 (Westward Movement) (Box 35)
  - Lecture notes, reading lists, seating charts, examinations, syllabuses, relevant clippings and articles, etc. for History 132 (Westward Movement); History 21; and History 122 (Box 36)
  - Lecture notes, reading lists, seating charts, examinations, syllabuses, relevant clippings and articles, etc. for History 122; and History 175; and Histry 12, 23; and History 162 (Box 37)
  - Miscellaneous speeches, clippings, students' book reports (Box 37)
  - Lecture notes, reading lists, seating charts, examinations, syllabuses, relevant clippings and articles, etc. for American Democracy (History 165) (Box 38)
  - Texts of various speeches. (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Texts of speeches, lectures for citizenship class. (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Typescripts of speeches, lectures (Box 39, Folder 3 - 6)
  - Typescripts of lectures, speeches, etc. (Box 40, Folder 7 - 11)
- Student Term Papers, 1893-1947 (Box 29)
  - 1. Albright, R.E. THE INFLUENCE OF THE PROGreSSIVE MOVEMENT OF CALIFORNIA IN THE CAMPAIGNS OF 1912-16, 1930
  - 2. Bancroft, Anne THE ACTIVITIES OF HENRY WAGER HALLECK IN CALIFORNIA 1847-61, 1930
  - 3. Burkett, Charles WILLIAM M. GWIN'S ACTIVITIES IN THE SENATE reLATIVE TO A PACIFIC RAILROAD, 1938
  - 4. Dale, Frances GOVERNMENT - BY THE FORTY-NINERS, 1947
  - 5. Desmond, Harold F. THE PANIC OF 1873 IN CALIFORNIA AND BUSINESS CONDITIONS IN 1874, 1917
  - 6. Forbes, Elizabeth CALIFORNIA NEWSPAPERS 1846-1860, 1934
  - 7. Fowler, Ruth M. CALIFORNIA'S PART IN THE CAMPAIGN OF 1896, 1925
  - 8. Fuller, Mort AN EXAMPLE OF reSEARCH, 1932
  - 9. Gaynor, Kathleen JOAQUIN MURIETA: A STUDY OF SOCIAL CONDITIONS IN CALIFORNIA IN THE EARLY FIFTIES
  - 10. Gray, Mary LELAND STANFORD AND THE EARLY rePUBLICAN PARTY IN CALIFORNIA, 1947
  - 11. Gregory, John M. A HISTORY OF THE LAW OF DECLAreD HOMESTEADS IN THE STATE OF CALIFORNIA, 1896
  - 12. Groves, J. Lowell THE BEGINNINGS OF FOreIGN TRADE IN SAN FRANCISCO, 1849-1859, 1935
  - 13. Hamilton, Patricia THE ESTABLISMENY AND EARLY DEVELOPMENT OF PUBLIC EDUCATION IN SAN FRANCISCO
  - 14. Hopler, Doris MINING IN CALIFORNIA, 1848-1853
  - 15. Ingraham, Alice FIRST NEWSPAPERS IN CALIFORNIA, 1846-1860, 1929
  - 16. Jacobson, David S. A SHORT SURVEY OF CALIFORNIA JOURNALISM, 1846-1852
  - 17. Krantz, Nettie E. THE PARTIES AND ISSUES IN CALIFORNIA, 1872, 1921
  - 18. Le Baker, Edwin H. THE NINTH GOVERNOR OF CALIFORNIA, FreDERICK FERDINAND LOW, 1939
  - 19. McSpadden, H. M. reLATIONS BETWEEN SAN FRANCISCO AND HONOLULU, 1848 to 1860, 1935
  - 20. McDowell, Jack DAVID COLBreTH BRODERICK, 1930
  - 21. Pickett, Barbara THE LIFE OF JOHN McDOUGAL, THE SECOND GOVERNOR OF CALIFORNIA, 1939
  - 22. Pillot, Mary THE ADMISSION OF CALIFORNIA
  - 23. Ralph, Harold E. THE DISCOVERY OF GOLD IN CALIFORNIA, 1936
  - 24. Russell, Jessie E. THE CONQUEST OF CALIFORNIA AND THE STRUGGLE IN CONGreSS FOR ITS ADMISSION INTO THE UNION, 1893
  - 25. Schuck, Victoria THE reLATION OF THE GOVERNOR AND THE LEGISLATUre IN CALIFORNIA, 1849-1852, 1930
  - 26. Stein, Joel AGENCIES OF THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT IN CALIFORNIA - 1860, 1938
  - 27. Swayze, Doris PreSIDENTIAL ELECTION OF 1864 IN CALIFORNIA, 1926
  - 28. Yost, Lucy S. POLITICAL ACTIVITIES OF THE BreCKENRIDGE PARTY IN CALIFORNIA, 1861, 1936
  - 29. Young, Barbara EARLY CALIFORNIA LEADERS AND THEIR INFLUENCE ON SLAVERY SENTIMENT IN CALIFORNIA, 1930
  - 30. Young, Barbara THOMAS STARR KING AND THE UNION AS SEEN THROUGH CONTEMPORARY NEWSPAPERS 1860-1864, 1930
  - 31. Young, Lucy HENRY W. BIGLER AND HIS DIARIES, AS SIDELIGHTS ON CALIFORNIA HISTORY FROM JULY, 1846 THROUGH SEPTEMBER, 1848, 1935
- Publications